# Sopan Masure

**Backend Developer** 

sopanmasure913@gmail.com 7745834339 | Pune Github | LinkedIn | Hackerrank

#### **SUMMARY**

With 2 years of experience, I specialize in Backed Development for scalable server–side solutions. Committed to delivering high–quality code, I possess strong problem–solving skills, attention to detail, and adaptability to work collaboratively or independently. Dedicated to ongoing skillset expansion and staying updated on industry trends.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Techspian Services**, Pune — Associate Software Developer

May 2022 - PRESENT

- Worked a 10-member team in the development and maintenance of a flight travel portal using NodeJS, JavaScript, and MongoDB, focusing on feature building and optimization.
- Actively collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure the timely delivery of the travel portal project.
- Resolved critical bugs and issues through thorough debugging, log analysis, and troubleshooting, utilizing microservices for efficient problem-solving.
- Implemented a subscription system using Node.js and MongoDB,including billing and user management.

## **Techspian Services,** Pune — *Intern*

March 2022 - May 2022

- Developed web applications using JavaScript and NodeJS. Gained experience in HTML, CSS and Mongodb.
- Actively participated in team discussions and contributed to project success through effective communication and collaboration.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming
  Languages C, C++
- Database SQL,
  MongoDB, Firebase
- Web Development HTML, CSS,
   JavaScript, NodeJS,
   Reactjs
- Mobile Development Flutter, Dart
- OS Linux (Ubuntu) , Windows
- Tools Github, Kibana

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Organized college level event (Texplorers).
- Organized workshops in university. (python, android, php)
- Participated in Smart India Hackathon.

#### **LANGUAGES**

ENGLISH, HINDI, MARATHI

### **PROJECTS**

## **Room Booking**

- The project is the development of a web application for online room booking for hostels. The application allows users to search for and book available rooms in hostels based on eligibility.
- Users or students can complete the booking procedure through our application, and admins can review the applicant's form. The application was developed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, and Node.js.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Dr.Babasaheb Ambedkar Technological University, Lonere

— Btech (Electronics And Telecomminication)

Sept 2019 - May 2022 GPA - 8.97

# **Institute of Petrochemical Engineering, Lonere**

— **Diploma**(Computer Engineering)

Aug 2016 - May 2018 GPA - 7.03